Many apps need to store information in files and
read information from files. Now that we know
how to open and close a file, let’s further
investigate how to read information from a
file. I have the same code example we have been
working on in this section, and in this version,
313-read, we will add a read statement to
read the file’s contents. Before doing that,
we need to ensure a file is open in read mode. The
code on line 6, which contains the open method,
has two arguments: the file we are opening
and the status of the file: r stands for read,
and r+ stands for both read and write. When
opening a file for reading purposes, one needs
to know whether some writing could also be needed
for the file. If not, the mode should be r and not
r+. On line 7, I will add code to read the file's
contents. The code is content=message_test.read().
We need a variable to store the contents of
the file being read. Then, on the next line,
I will add a print statement to print what has
been read. I will run the code. Right now, the
two lines of text appear as one line. The cause
of that is how the text is written to the file,
which will be addressed in the next topic. For
now, understand that for a file to be read,
it needs to be open in a kind of read mode.
The contents need to be stored in a variable,
and then the content can be disseminated
through a print statement. Otherwise,
a file can be opened, but we won’t be
able to see the contents of said file.